(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
いたずらに君をずっと見ていたわけじゃない
It's not like I was just staring at you for fun.
僕の考えを当ててごらんよ
Try to guess what I'm thinking.
ささやかなしぐさ 視線合った時
A subtle gesture, the moment our eyes met,
君はもう手のひらに
you were already in the palm of my hand.
むき出しのトラップ なんてかかるわけないわ
There's no way I'd fall for such an obvious trap.
甘い言葉にも惑わされない
I won't be swayed by sweet words either.
心の奥の奥の奥まで
To the deepest, deepest, deepest part of your heart,
見透かしてあげるよ
I'll see right through you.
Looking Thinking Nothing Feeling
By you know
Thinking Thinking Thinking
I know it
Looking Thinking Nothing Feeling
Thinking Thinking Thinking
Understand
Are you ready?
自覚はないでしょうね 思い通りに
You probably don't realize it, but exactly as I planned,
君は動かされていること
you're being manipulated.
単純じゃないの かけひきのヒートを
It's not simple. Don't let the heat of this bargaining...
冷めに落とさないで
...cool down or fade away.
加速してく
Accelerating,
二人の鼓動
our two heartbeats.
心理戦は次のステージへ
The psychological battle moves to the next stage.
うつろなその目に私はどう映るの
How do I look in those hollow eyes of yours?
煌びやかで まるでシンデレラ
Dazzling, just like Cinderella.
突き刺さる視線 ズキンと感じて
Feeling your piercing gaze like a throb,
君に余裕見せつけて
I'll show you my composure.
あからさますぎて お腹がよじれるよ
It's so obvious, my stomach is in knots from laughing.
すでに君はもう 焼き上がってる
You're already completely done for.
頭で次の次の次まで
In my head, to the next, next, next step,
見通さなくちゃ
I must see through it all.
Looking Thinking Touching Feeling
Feeling, Feeling, Feeling
Touching, Feeling
I know it
Feeling, Feeling, Feeling
Understand?
Of love
Hi Ready?
唯一無二のジョーカー 手にするために
To get the one and only Joker
欲望さらけ出してる本性
Revealing your true nature
離れていく世界のロジックを
The logic of the world moving away
君は楽しめるかな
I wonder if you'll be able to enjoy it
重要なキーは
The crucial key is
すべてシークレット
Everything is secret
後戻りはできないステージへ
To the stage from which there is no turning back
気づいているでしょ ここにいる意味さえも
You've noticed, haven't you? Even the meaning of being here
切り札はそれぞれ お互いの手札に
The trumps are in each other's hands
頭と心で暴走期待して
Expecting a rampage in head and heart
胸を撃ち抜け
Shoot through the chest
自覚ないでしょうね 思い通りに
You probably don't realize it, just as you planned
君は踊らされていること
That you're being made to dance
単純じゃないの 駆け引きのヒントを
It's not simple, the hints for the bargaining
すべて拾って
Pick them all up
唯一無二のジョーカー 手にすることで
By getting the one and only Joker
理解できた愛の形を
The shape of love I was able to understand
どこかの誰かに仕組まれていても
Even if it was set up by someone somewhere
最高に笑う君と
With you laughing at your best
加速していく
Accelerating
二人どこへ
Where are we going?
新時代は次のステージへ
The new era goes to the next stage
Please Mr. Silence
どうして どうして
Why, why
選べるのが 君しかいないんだ
You're the only one who can choose
お願い Choose me
Please Choose me
ほら 早く今日中に
Look, hurry up before today is over
お願い Choose me
Please Choose me
Choose me
君が今日選んでくれないとなにもできない
I can't do anything unless you choose today
考えてくれないと心配になっちゃうんだ
I'll get worried if you don't think about it
こんなところで 迷ってると沈むよ深海
If you hesitate here, you'll sink into the deep sea
沈むよ深海
You'll sink into the deep sea
濡れて気づいた...
I noticed when I got wet...
揺れる
Swaying,
震える体が
my trembling body
溢れてきちゃった
has started to overflow.
船底から
From the bottom of the ship,
穴が開いたんだ
a hole has opened.
脱走して
I escaped,
ああ どうして
ah, why
のぼせてるのが
am I so lightheaded...
君しかいないんだ
...only when I'm with you.
お願い シューリ
Please, repair me.
さあ ほら 今すぐ シューリ
Come on, right now, repair me.
急いで 熱中して
Hurry, get absorbed...
熱中して
...get absorbed.
君がよく再生してくれないと
If you don't regenerate me properly,
生きられない
I can't live.
感じてる そろそろ限界値
I'm feeling it, it's almost the limit.
大事なもの探しに行かない？
Won't you go find something important?
大体 夢の旅してたいに
Basically, I want to keep traveling in a dream.
君がいないと意味なんてない
It's meaningless without you.
考えてくれないと心配に
I'll get worried if you don't think about me.
感じちゃうんだ こんなところで
I end up feeling it, in a place like this.
迷ってるといけないよ 絶対に
You mustn't get lost, definitely.
いけないよ 絶対に
Definitely mustn't.
Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆
作詞：まろん (IOSYS) 作曲：ARM (IOSYS)
Ahoy!! We Are Houshou Pirates☆
Lyrics: Maron (IOSYS) Composition: ARM (IOSYS)
海賊ならヨーホー 踊り明かそうヨーホー
If you're a pirate, yo-ho! Let's dance the night away, yo-ho!
さあ 今 旗の下へ
Now, come beneath the flag!
宝鐘海賊団 出航！
Houshou Pirates, setting sail!
Ahoy!
踊るアホウに見るアホウ
Fools who dance and fools who watch,
Ahoy!
全速前進だー！
Full speed ahead!
進め！ 太陽は燦々 大航海日和だ
Advance! The sun is shining bright, it's a perfect day for a voyage.
歌え！ 最高のテンション 波の音に乗せて
Sing! With the highest tension, riding on the sound of the waves.
どんぶらこ海でガールズパーティー
Tumbling through the sea, it's a girls' party!
お宝 見っけりゃハッピー
If we find treasure, we're happy.
踊れば道楽 ギラギラ
Dancing is a pleasure, shining bright!
今日もボロボロ マイハウスで夢を見て
Dreaming again today in my run-down "my house"...
ああ、神様
Ah, God...
いつかこのマリンを 本物の海賊にしてください！
Please, someday, turn this Marine into a real pirate!
声を上げて さあ出航だ
Raise your voices, come on, we're setting sail!
我ら宝鐘海賊団
We are the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ
With a compass in one hand, raising the flag...
この海をジャックしちゃおう
...let's hijack this sea!
よそ見せず付いておいで
Follow me without looking away,
ともにヨーホー ヨーホー 叫ぼう
let's shout "yo-ho, yo-ho" together!
ああ 最高の連日
Ah, the best consecutive days.
ようこそ 我が船へ
Welcome to my ship!
Ahoy!
踊るアホウに見るアホウ
Fools who dance and fools who watch,
出航だホーイ！
Setting sail, ho-i!
1, 2, さんばー！ たんばー！
1, 2, Samba! Tambourine!
熱く語ろうよパッション 想いを解き放て
Let's talk passionately about our passion, set your feelings free!
煌めくファッション 形から入るタイプです
Sparkling fashion, I'm the type who starts with the appearance.
発射準備前 走れ
Run, before launch preparations!
抱っこしちゃお
Let's have a hug!
ぶっちゃけ照れるわ
I'm getting shy...
ギラギラ
Shining bright!
じんわり汗もしたたるいい女
A fine woman with sweat gently dripping,
だけど
however...
ああ、神様
Ah, God...
船長はセンシティブだと BANされちゃうのですねー！？
If the Captain is too sensitive, I'll get banned, won't I!?
はにゃ～
Hanya~
奪われたら取り戻せ
If it's taken from you, take it back!
それが宝鐘海賊団
That's the Houshou Pirates!
君たちとなら見つける
With all of you, I'll find it,
伝説のエルドラド
the legendary El Dorado!
よそ見せず楽しけりゃ
If you're having fun without looking away,
歌えヨーホー ヨーホー パリナイ
sing "yo-ho, yo-ho, party night!"
ああ この景色
Ah, this scenery.
大切な仲間よ
My precious crew!
宴だ宴 騒げや騒げ
It's a banquet, a banquet! Make some noise, make some noise!
踊るアホウに見るアホウ
Fools who dance and fools who watch,
同じアホなら飲まなきゃ損損
If we're the same fools, it's a loss if we don't drink!
酒樽片手に行きますよ
With a sake barrel in one hand, here I go!
ほれ Ahoy! Ahoy!
Now, Ahoy! Ahoy!
Ahoy!
宝鐘マリン！
Houshou Marine!
世界で一番
The best in the world!
メスガキ！メスガキ！
Brat! Brat!
エロガキ！エロガキ！
Lewd brat! Lewd brat!
ボンキュッボン！
Curvy and hot!
お嬢さん パンツ何色？
Young lady, what color are your panties?
お宝！お宝！
Treasure! Treasure!
もぞい！もぞい！
Embarrassing! Embarrassing!
のーでもすぞん
No- de mosuzon
船長のちょっといいとこ
Captain's good points
見てみたい！
I want to see!
アハン　ウフン（ホッサ！ホッサ！）
A-han, U-hun (Ho-sa! Ho-sa!)
ンフン　ンフン（ホッサ！ホッサ！）
N-hun, N-hun (Ho-sa! Ho-sa!)
セクシーリン（ホッサ！ホッサ！）
Sexy lean (Ho-sa! Ho-sa!)
いやんまいしんぐ（ホッサ！ホッサ！）
Oh my, moving forward (Ho-sa! Ho-sa!)
だっちゅーの（ホッサ！ホッサ！）
Dacchu-no! (Ho-sa! Ho-sa!)
サビサビつ（ホッサ！ホッサ！）
Service, service! (Ho-sa! Ho-sa!)
萌え萌えキュン（ホッサ！ホッサ！）
Moe moe kyun! (Ho-sa! Ho-sa!)
出会って５秒で（ホッサ！ホッサ！）
Within 5 seconds of meeting (Ho-sa! Ho-sa!)
あーもう！船長は君たちをそんな風に育てた覚えはありません！
Ah, geez! Captain doesn't remember raising you all like that!
本当に...
Seriously...
...ね、だぞ！
...you know, dazo!
立てば芍薬、座れば牡丹
Standing like a peony, sitting like a tree peony
歩く姿は…センシティブ！
Walking like a... sensitive!
夢の海（みん）は　この船で　後悔なんてさせない
On this ship, I won't let your dream voyage end in regret
君たちのおかげで　私は船長になれるから
Because thanks to all of you, I can be a captain
皆様船長から？（オッケー！）
Everyone, from the Captain? (OK!)
声を上げて出航だ　我ら宝鐘海賊団
Raise your voices, it's time to set sail! We are the Houshou Pirates!
本八　片手に旗を揚げ　この海をジャックしちゃおう
With a Honpatsu in one hand, raise the flag and let's jack this sea!
ヨーソロー付いておいで　共にヨーホーヨーホー叫ぼう
Steady as she goes, follow me! Let's shout Yo-ho, Yo-ho together!
あぁ　最高の日々
Ah, these best of days!
ようこそ我が船へ
Welcome to my ship
宝鐘の海賊団！
The Houshou Pirates!
それではいきますよ！
Here we go!
出航！
Set sail!
はい！ということで…立て続けに、えー、３曲聴いていただきました。ありがとうございます！君たち、アホイ！
All right! So... I've performed three songs in a row for you. Thank you! Ahoy to you all!
はい。ということでね、ちょっとまずさ、君たち…ま、気付くことちょっと２つくらいないかな？何か。
Yes. So, first of all, guys... are there maybe two things you've noticed? Anything?
気付いてほしいな～　コメントで指摘されたいな～
I want you to notice~ I want it pointed out in the comments~
じゃ、その１。見てください！
Well, number one. Look at this!
このステージ！
This stage!
わー！ちょっとね、あの、船長風に作ってもらいました。
Wow! It was made, you know, in a Captain-style.
どうですか？素敵でしょう？
What do you think? Isn't it wonderful?
今日はここで歌って踊ってしていきたいと思うのでね、存分に見ていってください！
I'm going to sing and dance here today, so please enjoy the show to the fullest!
もう一個あるよね？
There's one more thing, right?
気付かれたい、乙女心。
A maiden's heart wants to be noticed.
じゃーん！この帽子です！
Ta-da! It's this hat!
ちょっとね、船長の頭があまりにも丸いのでね、ちょっと付けてもらいました。
Well, the Captain's head is just so round, so I had this added.
どうですか？確かに丸い頭も可愛いけど、この尖りみが可愛いでしょ？
How is it? Sure, a round head is cute, but this pointed look is cute too, right?
これでね、より海賊感が増したかと思います！
I think this makes me look even more like a pirate!
そして今日はね、今日は何のライブですか？はい！今日のライブは、マリン出航お披露目ライブ！
And today, what kind of live is it? Yes! Today's live is the 'Marine Set Sail Reveal Live'!
ということで。ま、実はもうお披露目…ちょっとサードライブでしちゃったんですけど。
That's right. Well, actually, I already revealed it... a bit during the 3rd live.
まだ見れてない人もいるんじゃないかな？今日初めて聞くって人もいるんじゃないかな？
But maybe some people haven't seen it yet? Maybe some are hearing it for the first time today?
船長にとって、もうとっても、とっても大事な一曲になっていますので、今日はしっかり聴いてくださいよ！
It's a very, very important song for the Captain, so please listen closely today!
そしてね、このあと…ま察しも付いてるかもしれませんが、22時に…なんかプレミア公開がありますよね？
And, after this... you might have already guessed, but at 10 PM... there's a premiere, right?
ちょっとすごいね、すごいことになってるから、もうそこも絶対見てほしい！重大発表のひとつです。
It's something really amazing, so I definitely want you to watch that too! It's one of the major announcements.
てなわけで、このあとはちょっとやっぱり一人じゃね、さすがに寂しいなと思ったので、いろんなホロメンと歌っていきたいと思いますので！
So, after this, I thought it would be a bit lonely to be by myself, so I'm going to sing with various Hololive members!
それでは、ゲストパートに、んー、出航！
Now, for the guest part... set sail!
インドア系ならトラックメーカー
作詞：Yunomi nicamoq　作曲：Yunomi
Indoor-kei nara Trackmaker
Lyrics: Yunomi nicamoq　Composition: Yunomi
My house is the world, new house, electro house
トラックメーカー　通勤ラッシュ
Trackmaker, commuting rush
アップロード　アテンションマックス
Upload, attention max
ハウスダスト　ノンフィクション
House dust, non-fiction
花粉症にはマスクメロン
Musk melon for hay fever
カーソル待ってよクラクション　ほらクリックリリリ　トラックメーカー
Cursor wait, klaxon, look click-ri-ri-ri, trackmaker
お洒落な曲地とファッションセンター
Stylish local area and fashion center
両手を掲げてクラッピョハンザ
Raise both hands, clap-yo-hands-up
ジャージにワイシャツ絶対ヘンダー
Jersey and dress shirt, definitely strange
MIDIトラックメーカー
MIDI trackmaker
お洒落なベンチとファッションセンター
Stylish bench and fashion center
両手を掲げてクラッピョハンザ
Raise both hands, clap-yo-hands-up
脳ギアスター絶対徹夜
No gear star, definitely all-nighter
Every everynight トラックメーカー
Every everynight trackmaker
フットダンス
Foot dance
お酒も入ってそこそこナイス
A bit of alcohol, feeling pretty nice
ネクタイ緩めた今こそチャンス
Loosened the tie, now's the chance
クラブチメガネに細身のパンツ
Club sunglasses and slim pants
二人を揺るがすワブルなベース
Wobble bass shaking the two of us
今夜は残念玉砕です
Tonight, unfortunately, is a crushing defeat
オシャレの極致だファッションセンター
The height of style, Fashion Center
両手を掲げてクラップユアヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
掃除に掃除はアウトドア派
Cleaning, cleaning, outdoor types
インドア系ならトラックメイカー
If you're the indoor type, then a track maker
オシャレの聖地だファッションセンター
The holy land of style, Fashion Center
両手を掲げてクラップユアヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
キーボード叩け夜明け前まで
Tap the keyboard until dawn
眠気のピークにカフェイン投下
Injecting caffeine at the peak of sleepiness
眠気のピークにカフェイン投下！
Injecting caffeine at the peak of sleepiness!
オシャレの極致だファッションセンター
The height of style, Fashion Center
両手を掲げてクラップユアヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
ジャージにワイシャツ絶対変だ
Jersey and dress shirt, definitely weird
MIDIトラックメイカー
MIDI Track Maker
オシャレの聖地だファッションセンター
The holy land of style, Fashion Center
両手を掲げてクラップユアヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
納期は明日だ絶対徹夜
Deadline is tomorrow, definitely staying up all night
エビデーエビナイ トラックメイカー
Every day, every night, Track Maker
オシャレの極致だファッションセンター
The height of style, Fashion Center
両手を掲げてクラップユアヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
ジャージにワイシャツ絶対変だ
Jersey and dress shirt, definitely weird
MIDIトラックメイカー
MIDI Track Maker
オシャレの聖地だファッションセンター
The holy land of style, Fashion Center
両手を掲げてクラップユアヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
納期は明日だ絶対徹夜
Deadline is tomorrow, definitely staying up all night
エビデーエビナイ トラックメイカー
Every day, every night, Track Maker
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center
クラップユアヘンザ
Clap your hands up
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center
クラップユアヘンザ
Clap your hands up
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center
クラップユアヘンザ
Clap your hands up
はぁ〜〜〜い！お疲れ様でーす！
Haaai! Great job!
かなたんありがとう！
Kanatan, thank you!
いえーい、お邪魔しまーす。
Yay, thanks for having me.
今回のこの「インドア系ならトラックメイカー」は、かなたが選んでくれたんだよね。
Kanata chose "Indoors-y Track Maker" for this time, right?
そうなんです。ちょっとね、僕たちの可愛い可愛い萌え声に合うかなって思ってにゃ。
That's right. I thought it might suit our cute, cute moe voices, nya.
そうだよね！マリン、マリンちゃんも頑張ってすごい萌え声で歌ったった。
Right! Marine, Marine-chan also did her best to sing with a very moe voice.
よ、よ、よ、よ、よ、よ...皆さん、あのー、すみません。マリンたんのちょっと無理した萌え声をね、お届けする形になってしまって申し訳ございません。
Yo, yo, yo... Everyone, um, I'm sorry. I'm sorry for delivering Marine-tan's somewhat forced moe voice.
ほんとキツい、こんなキツいもの聴かせてしまって、ほんとすみません。
It's really tough, I'm so sorry for making you listen to something so tough.
キツくございませんわ！
It's not tough at all!
まぁまぁ、でもマリンたん、今日は、マリン、今日はね、おめでたい日なので。
Well, well, but Marine-tan, today is, Marine, today is a celebratory day.
あ、そうだね！喧嘩はやめよう、喧嘩はやめよう。そうだよ。喧嘩しないで仲良しで終わろう。
Ah, that's right! Let's stop fighting, let's stop fighting. Let's not fight and end on good terms.
あ、でもさ、これさ、歌い出だすまであるよね！これ神だったから、出来映えが。ちょっとこれ形に残したいなって思っている。
Ah, but, this, it's worth singing again! Because it was divine, the quality. I'm thinking I want to preserve this somehow.
え、ね、わかる。出たかもしれないなっていう伏線を出しながら...な、にゃ？
Yeah, I know. While dropping hints that it might have come out... na, nya?
じゃ、仲良く終わろっか。
Then, shall we end on good terms?
そうだね。じゃちょっとハート作って終わろっか。
Right. Then let's make a heart and end it.
いいよいいよ。たまにはね、ちょっと尊いとこ出しとこうね。
Sure, sure. Let's show a precious side once in a while.
そうだね、ちょっとてぇてぇな。じゃマリンたん行くよ。
Right, a bit tee-tee. Then, Marine-tan, here we go.
行くよ。
Here we go.
せーの！
Ready, set, go!
バラライカ
Balalaika
ゆらり　ゆらり　揺れている
Swaying, swaying
乙女心ピンチ
A maiden's heart in a pinch
かなり　かなり　やばいのよ
It's quite, quite bad
助けてダーリンくらっくらに
Help me darling, I'm dizzy
なにもかもが　あたらしい
Everything is new
世界にきちゃったわ
I've come to a new world
たくさんのドキドキ
So much excitement
乗り越え　踏み越え　行くわよ
Overcoming and stepping over them, here I go
バラライカ　バララライカ　バラライカ
Balalaika, Balala-laika, Balalaika
この思いは止められない
I can't stop these feelings
もっとドラマチック・パワー
More dramatic power
きなりに超・急・接近
Suddenly, ultra-close approach
バラライカ　バララライカ　バラライカ
Balalaika, Balala-laika, Balalaika
もうドキドキ止められない
Can't stop the heart-pounding anymore
もっとドラマチック・恋
More dramatic love
ハレルヤフ　二人だけのバラライカ
Hallelujah, a Balalaika for just the two of us.
すごくすごく近づいて
Coming very, very close,
乙女心チャンス
it's a chance for a maiden's heart.
ハート　ハート　飛び出そう
My heart, heart is about to jump out.
おねがいダーリン　ハラハリン
Please darling, I'm so nervous.
あなただけを見つめてるわ　ワタシにしらんぷり
I'm only looking at you, but you're ignoring me.
気づいてほしいのよ
I want you to notice
トキメキヤキモチ　ツキヨ
the heartbeat, the jealousy, on this moonlit night.
バラライカ　バラライカ　バラライカ　ヨ
Balalaika, Balalaika, Balalaika, yo!
この秘密を教えてよ
Tell me this secret.
もっともっとマジックもっとピラリニ
More and more magic, more pirari-ni.
やっぱ笑顔がステキ
After all, your smile is wonderful.
バラライカ　バラライカ　バラライカ　ヨ
Balalaika, Balalaika, Balalaika, yo!
遠まわしじゃダメダメよ
Being indirect is no good.
もっとロマンチック恋シャラランカ
A more romantic love, shalala-nka.
奏でたいのバラライカ
I want to play the Balalaika.
女の子はいつだって夢見る乙女なの
Girls are always dreaming maidens.
ピュアピュアな心で
With a pure, pure heart,
恋して愛して　S・O・S
falling in love, loving, S.O.S.
S・O・S　バラライカ
S.O.S. Balalaika!
バラライカ　バラライカ　バラライカ　ヨ
Balalaika, Balalaika, Balalaika, yo!
この思いは止められない
This feeling cannot be stopped.
もっとマジックパワーピラリニ
More magic power, pirari-ni.
ちょっと危険な恋路
A slightly dangerous love path.
バラライカ　バラライカ　バラライカ　ヨ
Balalaika, Balalaika, Balalaika, yo!
ドキドキ止められない
The heartbeat cannot be stopped.
もっとロマンチック恋シャラランカ
A more romantic love, shalala-nka.
ハレルヤフ　二人だけのバラライカ
Hallelujah, a Balalaika for just the two of us.
はい、ということで、メルちゃんに来てもらいましたー！
Alright, and so, we have Mel-chan here!
こんかぷー！夜空メルだよー！
Konkapu! It's Yozora Mel!
あーメルちゃんありがとう！
Ah, Mel-chan, thank you!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
はい、今回曲の候補いろいろあったけど、結局これにした決め手は何でしょう？
Yes, there were many candidates for the song, but what was the deciding factor for choosing this one?
そりゃやっぱり、マリンもメルもニコ厨だからさー。
Well, that's obviously because both Marine and Mel are Nico Nico fans.
そうだね、我々ニコ厨ですからね。
Right, we are Nico Nico fans.
ねー。
Yeah.
ところでメルちゃん。
By the way, Mel-chan.
なに？
What?
船長の家に泊まりに来たときさー。
When you came to stay at Sencho's house...
うん。
Yeah.
勝負下着を着てきたのにマリンが即寝してショックだったって本当？
Is it true you were shocked because you wore showdown underwear but Marine fell asleep instantly?
本当だよ！マリンのバカー！
It's true! Marine, you dummy!
メルの勝負下着どうしてくれるの？
What are you going to do about Mel's showdown underwear?
ごめん、メル。
Sorry, Mel.
マリ…
Mari...
今からあの日のリベンジしよう。
Let's have a revenge for that day now.
お、おう。
O-oh.
ここ寝そべって。ここ寝て。はい。
Lie down here. Sleep here. Yes.
ここで？まじか。
Here? Seriously?
ムードも何もないじゃん。あ、はい寝て寝て。
There's no mood at all. Ah, alright, sleep, sleep.
はい、いくよ。
Alright, here I go.
うん。
Yeah.
メル…
Mel...
マリ…
Mari...
いいよ、来て。
It's okay, come.
あれ？
Huh?
マリ？
Mari?
あ、また寝てるじゃん！バカー！
Ah, she's sleeping again! Dummy!
半端ならKO
If it's half-hearted, it's a KO.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you want to feel fluffy, go ahead.
海戦準備しちゃお
Let's get ready for a naval battle.
泣いても笑っても愛してたまえ
Love me whether you cry or laugh.
ほら　せーの
Come on, one-two!
声を響かせろ
Let your voice ring out.
なんかもうつまんない
Somehow it's already boring.
ことば丸でしょう
It's just words, right?
ロリロリのノート　反比例本気ださー
Loli-loli notes, inverse proportion, get serious.
やめちゃってドロン
Quitting and disappearing,
一歩ハットだろが
that's one step forbidden, isn't it?
まじでアンパッテン　上がるまで待って
Seriously unpatterned, wait until it goes up.
繋がりのひとりよりふたり　増えたら安心　心配ないや
Better two than one connection; feel safe if they increase, no worries.
オレに任せてドマイ　波あり何だい　みんなで乗っちゃえば
Leave it to me, don't mind; what about the waves? Let's all ride them.
案外さくっといっちゃいそう
Seems like we'll go through easily unexpectedly.
半端ならKO
If it's half-hearted, it's a KO.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you want to feel fluffy, go ahead.
海戦準備しちゃお
Let's get ready for a naval battle.
泣いても笑っても愛してたまえ
Love me whether you cry or laugh.
ほら　せーの
Come on, one-two!
声を響かせろ
Let your voice ring out.
今宵はアンパッテンパーティ
Tonight is an unpatterned party.
踊り明かせ　踊り明かせ
Dance the night away, dance the night away.
孤独は先払いして
Paying for loneliness in advance.
Woah-oh-oh!
地平線までごシェアで　心で出番で Let's go!
Share it all to the horizon, it's our heart's turn, Let's go!
どうなることかな　どうです今日のご機嫌盤は
I wonder how it'll go, how's the mood board today?
さあコンテスト　混同してしまっちゃうんでしょ Oh yeah!
Come on, a contest, we're bound to get mixed up, right? Oh yeah!
アップダウンなテンションで参っちゃってんの早々
Up and down goes the tension, I'm already losing it.
ドバッと吹き出すのは　本音の独り言
What's gushing out is a monologue of true feelings.
全然興味ない！
Not interested at all!
特に勘弁ない！
Especially no mercy!
伏せ込んで　絶対絶対！？
Lying low, absolutely, absolutely!?
合図を奏でて　ブラブラブラ　Yeah yeah!
Play the signal, blah blah blah, Yeah yeah!
ほら集まって　夜更けだ！
Look, gather round, it's late at night!
Yeah yeah! 鳴いていこう！
Yeah yeah! Let's howl out!
パランパランパランパラン...
Param param param param...
ハチャメチャになっちゃえよ！
Let's go crazy!
Woah-oh-oh!
踊りだせ　踊りだせ　孤独はさっき舞い踊れ
Dance, dance, dance away the loneliness from before.
Woah-oh-oh!
地平線までごシェアで　今宵もあっぱれパーティータイム
Share it all to the horizon, another splendid party time tonight.
Woah-oh-oh!
笑ったもん勝ちを　いざ召し上がれ
Victory goes to the one who laughs, now help yourselves.
Woah-oh-oh!
地平線までお元気で　ここらでバイバイ Let's go!
Stay well all the way to the horizon, bye-bye for now, Let's go!
あはは！ということで、ポルカちゃんが来てくれましたー！
Ahahaha! So, Polka-chan joined us!
おわり尾丸ポルカでしたー！
That's all from Omaru Polka!
Yeah! Yeah!
マブダチ感あふれてる！
We're giving off total bestie vibes!
色合いがさ、ちょうどいいよねこのステージ。
The colors of this stage are just perfect, aren't they?
そうなのそうなの、このステージとね。
Exactly, exactly, with this stage and everything.
船長とポルカってさ、揃ったらさ、うちら無敵感あるじゃん。
When Senchou and Polka get together, we feel invincible, don't we?
え、なに？マブダチ？
Wait, what? Besties?
マブダチだよね！ずっとだよね！
We're besties, right? Forever, right?
ポルカとの思い出全然ないけどな。
I have zero memories with you though.
最悪なのお前！帰れよ！お前が帰れよ！
You're the worst! Go home! You go home!
出航！！
Set sail!!
あ、待って、誕生日尺あるから、ちょっとまだ帰らないで。
Wait, I have a birthday segment, so don't leave just yet.
尺とか言うなよ！
Don't call it a "segment"!
まだ帰らないで、もうちょっと話そう？
Don't leave yet, let's talk a bit more.
あのさ、どこに出航するの？これって。どっか行っちゃうの？
By the way, where are we setting sail to? Are you going somewhere?
君の心に出航！
Setting sail for your heart!
ポルカも出航しちゃいそうな気分になってきた？
Are you starting to feel like setting sail too, Polka?
ポルカもなんか出航したい！マリンで出航したいな。
I want to set sail too! I want to set sail with Marine.
え、ちょっとそれ隠語だからやめてください。
Hey, that sounds like slang, so please stop.
なんなんだよ！出航ってなんなの？
Come on! What even is "setting sail"?
じゃあここで聞くけど。
Well, I'll ask you right here.
え、ここで今ここで言うんですか！？
What, you're going to say it here, right now!?
あ、ごめんなさい時間なんで、ポルカ帰ります！
Oh, sorry, out of time, so I'm heading out!
バイバイ！
Bye bye!
出航！ヤサロス！
Set sail! Yasoros!
正しさとは
What is righteousness?
愚かさとは
What is foolishness?
それが何か見せつけてやる
I'll show you exactly what they are.
ちっちゃな頃から優等生　気づいたら大人になっていた
A model student since I was small, before I knew it, I'd grown up.
ナイフのような思考回路　持ち合わせる訳もなく
With no such thing as a razor-sharp thought process.
でも遊び足りない　何か足りない　困っちまうこれは誰かのせい
But I haven't played enough, something's missing, it's a problem and it's someone's fault.
あてもなくただ混乱するエイデイ
Just aimlessly confused every day.
最新の流行は当然の把握　経済の動向も通勤時チェック
Naturally grasping the latest trends, checking economic shifts during the commute.
純情な精神で入社しは　社会人じゃ当然のルールです
Joining the company with a pure spirit, it's a natural rule for a working adult.
はぁ？うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ　あなたが思うより健康です
Huh? Shut up, shut up, shut up, I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切凡庸な　あなたじゃ分からないかもね
Being completely and utterly mediocre, you probably wouldn't understand.
あぁよく似合う　その可もなく不可もないメロディ
Ah, it suits you well, that melody that's neither good nor bad.
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ　頭の出来が違うので問題はナシ
Shut up, shut up, shut up, our brains are built differently, so there's no problem.
つっても私も半人前　殴ったりするのはノーサンキュー
That said, I'm still just a novice, so no thanks to the punching.
うっせぇわ
Usseewa
身体ならば言葉の銃口を
If it's my body, I'll put the muzzle of words...
その頭に突き付けて撃てば
...against your head and fire!
マジヤバない？ 止まれやしない
Isn't it seriously bad? I won't stop.
不平不満垂れて成れの果て
Complaining and grumbling, look what you've become.
サディスティックに変貌する精神
A mind that transforms sadistically.
クソだりぃな
It's so damn annoying.
酒が空いたグラスあればすぐに注ぎなさい
If there's an empty glass, pour some sake immediately.
皆がつまみやすいように串外しなさい
Remove the skewers so everyone can easily grab the snacks.
会計や注文は先陣を切る
Be the first to settle the bill or order.
不文律最低限のマナーです
It's an unwritten rule, the bare minimum of manners.
はぁ？うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Huh? Shut up, shut up, shut up!
成功は口癖じゃ限界で
Saying "success" is just a habit, I'm at my limit.
絶対絶対現代の代弁者は私やろがい
I'm definitely the spokesperson for this modern era!
もう見飽きたわ 二番煎じかのパロディ
I'm tired of seeing these second-hand parodies.
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
丸々と肉付いたその顔面にバツ
A cross on that fat, fleshy face of yours!
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
私が俗に言う天才です
I'm what people call a genius.
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切凡庸なあなたじゃ分からないかもね
You, who are so mediocre, probably won't understand any of it.
嗚呼つまらねぇ
Ah, how boring.
何回聞かせるんだそのメモリー
How many times are you going to make me listen to that memory?
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
アタシも大概だけど
I'm quite something too, but...
どうだっていいぜ問題はなし
Whatever, there's no problem.
はい！というわけで、あくたんとミオ先輩が来てくれました！
Hi! So, Akutan and Mio-senpai have joined us!
はーい！ありがとう！来たよー！
Hi! Thank you! We're here!
せっかくこの三人で揃ったので、社会への不満を叫びましょう！
Since the three of us are here, let's shout out our frustrations with society!
社会への不満！？
Frustrations with society!?
社会への不満かー。
Frustrations with society, huh...
じゃあ船長からいきますよ。
Then I'll go first.
あるんだ。何だろう？
You have some? I wonder what.
バーナス、ミカンの次は、タラ！！
Barnas, Mikan, and then... TARA!!
それ普通にあの、社長への不満じゃんそれは！
That's just a frustration with the CEO!
あ、じゃあ、ミオ先輩ありますか？
Oh, then, Mio-senpai, do you have any?
えー、なんだろうなー。お、あ、あるあるある。やろう。
Hmm, what could it be... Oh, wait, I have one. Let's do it.
お、いきます？はい。
Oh, you're going? Okay.
オオカミ、周りが遠吠えしたら、なぜか勝手に遠吠えしてしまーう！！
As a wolf, when others around me howl, I somehow end up howling too without thinking!!
あ、本当の社会の話。
Oh, a story about real society.
嫌だったんだね、実は嫌だったんだ。
So you hated it. Actually, you hated it.
不思議だなーと思って。
I just thought it was strange.
嫌だったんだね。
So you hated it.
え、あくたん何かありますか？
Uh, Akutan, do you have anything?
社会への不満かー。うーん。あ、分かりました。
Frustrations with society, huh... Hmm. Oh, I've got it.
お、なんだろう。
Oh, I wonder what it is.
いいですか？お願いします！
Ready? Please!
ボッチで何が悪い！！
WHAT'S WRONG WITH BEING A LONER!!
社長ー！！あくたん！！
CEO!! Akutan!!
あくたん、ぼっちじゃないよ！
Akutan, you're not a loner!
そうだよ、私たちがついてる！
That's right, we're with you!
二人ともー！
You two...!
付いてますよ社長！
We're with you, CEO!
あ、すみません、ちょっともう時間なんで帰ってもらっていいですか？
Oh, sorry, we're out of time, so could you please head back?
あ、社長、行きましょう、帰り。時間なんで。
Oh, CEO, let's go, let's head back. It's time.
えー！嫌だ嫌だ嫌だ！待って待って！
What! No, no, no! Wait, wait!
いってらっしゃーい！バイバーイ！
Have a safe trip! Bye-bye!
空色デイズ
Sorairo Days
君は聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
僕のこの声が
This voice of mine?
闇に虚しく吸い込まれた
Empty, it was swallowed by the darkness.
もしも世界が意味を持つのなら
If the world were to have a meaning...
こんな気持ちも無駄ではない
Then even these feelings wouldn't be in vain.
憧れに押しつぶされて
Crushed by my yearnings,
諦めてたんだ
I had given up.
果てしない空の色も知らないで
Without even knowing the color of the endless sky.
走り出した
These feelings that started running,
思いが今でも
even now,
この胸の確かに叩いてるから
they are surely beating in this chest.
今日も僕が
Today, I will continue on
その先に続く
ahead,
僕なりの明日を築いていく
building my own tomorrow.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer is, yes, always right here.
過ぎた奇跡を 嘆く暇ない
No time to mourn the miracles of the past
二度と迷って しまわぬように
So I won't get lost again
数えきれない ほんのささやかな
Countless, tiny...
そんな後悔 抱えたまま
...regrets, I'll keep holding onto them
そんな背中だけ 追いかけて ここまで来たんだ
I've come this far just chasing that back
探していた 僕だけにできること
Looking for what only I can do
あの日くれた 言葉が今でも
The words you gave me that day, even now...
この胸に確かに 届いてるから
...are definitely reaching this heart
昨日よりも 今日僕は僕の
More than yesterday, today I...
生まれてきた 理由に気づいてゆく
...am realizing the reason I was born
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer is, yes, always right here
全てが回るね 当たり前みたいだ
Everything turns, like it's natural
尊い日々は まだ終わらない そして...
The precious days are not over yet, and...
また...
...again...
走り出した 思いが今でも
The feelings that started running, even now...
この胸を確かに 叩いてるから
...are definitely beating in this chest
今日の僕が その先につづく
The me of today will continue beyond...
僕らなりの 明日を築いてゆく
...to build our own tomorrow
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer is, yes, always right here
はぁ〜！
Haah!
あ〜！あやめ先輩、もう！
Ah! Ayame-senpai, jeez!
はい！
Yes!
なんかこういうライブみたいなやつ、
あやめ先輩と歌って踊るのもう何回目ですかね
Something like this live concert,
how many times has it been singing and dancing with Ayame-senpai?
4回目ぐらい？ 3？
Maybe about the 4th time? 3?
え、それってもうかなりラブラブっぷりですよね
Eh, that's already quite a lovey-dovey relationship, isn't it?
え？ 今日はなんて呼んでくれたの？
Eh? What did you call me today?
あ、アイスとか…
Ah, ice or something...
ガチで鳥肌立ってきた今
I'm literally getting goosebumps right now.
あやめ…いや、あやめちん
Ayame... no, Ayame-chin.
そのさ、あやめちんってあれ？
もしかして、もしかして、あれですか？
That 'Ayame-chin', is it...
could it be, could it be that?
そう、ちょっと振付の動画を前に出していたんですけど、カンニングしながら…
Yeah, I put out a choreography video before,
while cheating (looking at it)...
カンニングしながらね、ちょっと私たち練習してたんですけど
While cheating, we were practicing a bit.
これ反転してたらね
If this was mirrored...
そう、反転したほうが踊りやすいんだよね
Yeah, it's easier to dance if it's mirrored.
あやめちんマリンちんになってたわ
It became Ayame-chin Marine-chin.
そう、さ（SA）が繋がってるやつで、
そう、ひっくり返って『ちん（CHIN）』に見えたんですよね
Yeah, the 'SA' was connected, and
it looked like 'CHIN' when flipped.
ね。え、まさかこの話で終わりですか？
これもう1分経ってる？ もしかして
Right. Eh, are we seriously ending with this story?
Has it already been a minute? Maybe?
ちょ、あ、時間、時間だ！
Wait, ah, time, it's time!
あ、ちょ、待って！ 待って待って！
Ah, wait! Wait, wait!
待って！ 時間お願いします！
まだちょっと愛してる、愛してる、愛してる
Wait! Time please!
Still a bit... I love you, I love you, I love you.
時間お願いします！ 愛してる！ あー、あやめー！
Time please! I love you! Ah, Ayame-!
ヒトリゴトだよ 恥ずかしいこと聞かないでよね
It's a monologue, don't ask embarrassing things, okay?
君のことだよ でもその先は言わないけどね
It's about you, but I won't say any more than that.
掛け違えてるボタンみたいな もどかしさを
The frustration, like buttons done up wrong.
ほどけないまま また難しくしようとしてる
Without unravelling it, trying to make it difficult again.
伝えたい気持ちは今日も
The feelings I want to convey, today too...
言葉になる直前に
...just before they turn into words...
変換ミスの連続で
...are a series of conversion errors...
ため息と一緒に
...along with a sigh...
...呑み込んだ
...swallowed.
「ごめんね」を吐き出すには　程遠い
It's still far from being able to spit out "I'm sorry."
ふとした時に探しているよ
I find myself looking for you at unexpected times,
君の笑顔を探しているよ
looking for your smile.
無意識の中
Deep in my subconscious,
その理由は　まだ言えないけど
the reason for that, I still can't say.
独りでいると会いたくなるよ
When I'm alone, I start wanting to see you.
誰といたって会いたくなるよ
No matter who I'm with, I want to see you.
たった一言　「ねぇ、どうして？」
Just one word, "Hey, why?"
言えないこの言葉
These words I can't say,
言えないこの気持ち　Ah
these feelings I can't say, Ah.
早く気づいてほしいのに
Even though I want you to notice soon.
1000ピースあるパズルみたいな選択肢と
Choices like a 1,000-piece puzzle,
想像力が判断力の邪魔をしちゃう
imagination gets in the way of judgment.
掴めない気持ちは今日も
These elusive feelings, today too,
可愛くない顔見せて
showing a face that isn't cute,
自己嫌悪プラス後悔で
with self-loathing plus regret,
溜め込んだ「ごめんね」を吐き出すには　程遠い
it's still far from being able to spit out those bottled-up "I'm sorry"s.
耳を澄ませば聞こえてくるよ
If I listen closely, I can hear it,
君の声だけ聞こえてくるよ
I can hear only your voice.
雑踏の中
In the middle of the crowd,
気付かないふりしているけど
I pretend not to notice,
隣にいると嬉しくなるよ
when I'm next to you, I become happy.
遠くにいると寂しくなるよ
When you're far away, I become lonely.
単純なこと　でもどうして？
It's a simple thing, but why?
言えないこの言葉
These words I can't say,
言えないこの気持ち　Ah
these feelings I can't say, Ah.
もっと素直になりたい
I want to be more honest.
泣き出しそうな空模様
The sky looks like it's about to start crying.
頬にひと粒　雨かな...
A single drop on my cheek, is it rain...?
不安定な心隠した
I've hidden my unstable heart,
独り言に全部隠した
hidden it all in a soliloquy.
君のこと
About you,
本当はずっと... Ah...
actually, all along... Ah...
ふとした時に探しているよ
I find myself looking for you at unexpected times,
君の笑顔を探しているよ
looking for your smile.
無意識の中
Deep in my subconscious,
その理由は　まだ言えないけど
the reason for that, I still can't say.
独りでいると会いたくなるよ
When I'm alone, I start wanting to see you.
誰といたって会いたくなるよ
No matter who I'm with, I want to see you.
たった一言　「ねぇ、どうして？」
Just one word, "Hey, why?"
言えないこの言葉
These words I can't say,
言えないこの気持ち　Ah
these feelings I can't say, Ah.
早く気づいてほしいのに
Even though I want you to notice soon.
ぺこちゃん来てくれてありがとう！
Peko-chan, thanks for coming!
いえ、なんかすごい船ぺこね、ここね、なんか。
No, this is quite a ship, peko. This place, somehow.
そうなんですよ。乗せてやろうか、この船に。
That's right. Shall I let you on board this ship?
いや、もう降りるぺこ。
No, I'm getting off now, peko.
ちょ、待って待って。まだ早い。
Wait, wait. It's too soon.
お話しよう、お話しよう。
Let's talk, let's talk.
でも「独り言」っていう曲ね、ぺこちゃんが提案してくれたんだよね。
But the song "Hitorigoto", Peko-chan, you were the one who suggested it, right?
あれ、そうぺこっけ？
Wait, was that so, peko?
ぺこちゃん...忘れないで。
Peko-chan... don't forget.
でもぺこら思ったの。
But Pekora thought...
一緒に歌って踊って、ぺこまりってエモくできるんだって。
Singing and dancing together, Peko-Mari can actually be "emotional."
なーにが「エモくできるんだって」だよ。なれるよ、いつだって。
What do you mean "can be emotional"? We can be, anytime!
ほら、今エモい、エモいうちら、エモいうちらの図。
Look, right now, we're emotional. A shot of us being emotional.
ねえ、愛想笑いやん。なんか微妙な顔して。
Hey, that's a fake smile. You've got such a subtle face.
笑って笑って、はいチーズ。
Smile, smile, say cheese!
ねえ！嘘くさい！嘘くさいね、笑顔が！
Hey! That's so fake! That's a fake smile!
でもこの歌ね、ぺこらさんが二人で歌ってなったぺこだからさ。
But this song, Pekora thought of it because we'd be singing as a duo, peko.
二人で歌える曲で何があるかなって思った時に、「この曲いいじゃん！」ってね、
When I thought about what songs we could sing together, I thought "This song is good!"
「独り言」を提案したらマリンも乗っかってくれたから。
and when I suggested "Hitorigoto," Marine hopped on board too.
めっちゃ嬉しかったぺこ。
I was super happy, peko.
今終わらせようとしてるでしょ。まだ終わらせないよ。
You're trying to end it now, aren't you. I'm not letting it end yet.
そろそろ時間だぺこ。
It's about time, peko.
もっと二人の尊い話とかして。
Talk more about precious stories of us two.
ぺこまりは真実！
Peko-Mari is real!
お別れだ。
It's time for goodbye.
てをつなごう　いっしょにわらおう
Let's hold hands, let's laugh together.
ともだちになろう
Let's become friends.
ぼくのみぎてときみのひだりてを
If I try connecting my right hand and your left hand,
つないでみたら　なんだかうれしくなったよ
somehow, I started feeling happy.
ぼくのみぎてときみのみぎてで
If I shake hands with my right hand and your right hand,
あくしゅをしたら　さみしくなくなったよ
I stopped feeling lonely.
ラミィさんの右手と船長の左手
Lamy-san's right hand and the Captain's left hand
船長の右手とラミィさんの左手
The Captain's right hand and Lamy-san's left hand
船長の右手とノエルさんの左手
The Captain's right hand and Noel-san's left hand
ノエルさんの右手と船長の左手
Noel-san's right hand and the Captain's left hand
ママちゃんの右手とちまちゃんの左手
Mama-chan's right hand and Chima-chan's left hand
ちまちゃんの右手とダイスケさんの右手と
Chima-chan's right hand and Daisuke-san's right hand,
ガッチリ握手してください！
please shake hands firmly!
いつのまにか地球はくるり
Before you know it, the Earth is spinning
沖縄買って来たよー！
I bought Okinawa and came back!
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
いっしょに笑おう
Let's laugh together
ともだちになろう
Let's become friends
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
心つなごう
Let's connect our hearts
ぼくらはなかまさ
We are comrades
ハムー！ ハムー！ ハムー！
Ham! Ham! Ham!
ぼくの小指と君の小指で
With my pinky and your pinky
約束しよう、いつまでも仲よし
Let's make a promise to be friends forever
うれしいときも
When we're happy
ケンカしても
Even if we fight
はなれていても
Even if we're apart
ぼくたちはともだち
We are friends
ドラムちゃんの小指とノブさんの小指
Drum-chan's pinky and Nobu-san's pinky
ノブさんの小指とアブラさんの小指
Nobu-san's pinky and Abura-san's pinky
アブラさんの小指とババさんの小指
Abura-san's pinky and Baba-san's pinky
ババさんの小指とテラさんの小指
Baba-san's pinky and Tera-san's pinky
テラさんの小指とドラムさんの小指
村上さんは右手と間瀬さんと中田さんも握手してください
Tera-san's pinky and Drum-chan's pinky
Murakami-san, Mase-san, and Nakata-san, please shake hands
一丁かきひと世界中が
The whole world in one gulp
みんなともだちになれるよ！
Everyone can become friends!
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
いっしょに笑おう
Let's laugh together
ともだちになろう
Let's become friends
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
心つなごう
Let's connect our hearts
ぼくらはなかまさ
We are comrades
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
いっしょに笑おう
Let's laugh together
ともだちになろう
Let's become friends
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
心つなごう
Let's connect our hearts
ぼくらはなかまさ
We are comrades
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
いっしょに笑おう
Let's laugh together
ともだちになろう
Let's become friends
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
心つなごう
Let's connect our hearts
ぼくらはなかまさ
We are comrades
手をつなごう 手をつなごう
Let's hold hands, let's hold hands
ラララララララララララ
Lalalalala...
手をつなごう 手をつなごう
Let's hold hands, let's hold hands
ぼくらはなかまさ
We are comrades
あつーい！ すごい！ やばい、あつい！ 汗かいたね。
So hot! Amazing! Man, it's hot! We really sweated.
自己紹介スタート！ お前は？ どうぞ。
Self-introduction start! And you are? Go ahead.
やかましの「や」、ころねです！
The 'Ya' of Yakamashi, I'm Korone!
やかましの「か」、ラミィです！
The 'Ka' of Yakamashi, I'm Lamy!
やかましの「ま」、マリンです！
The 'Ma' of Yakamashi, I'm Marine!
やかましの「し」、ノエルです！
The 'Shi' of Yakamashi, I'm Noel!
四人合わせて、やかましフォー！
All four of us together, Yakamashi Four!
や、でもさ、集まったもののさ、うちらって結構裏で話すから、もう話すことないんだよね。
Well, even though we gathered, we talk a lot behind the scenes, so there's nothing left to talk about.
じゃ、解散しましょうか。
Well, shall we disband then?
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
3、2、1... あばよ！
3, 2, 1... See ya!
おいおいおい！ 待って待って待って！
Hey hey hey! Wait wait wait!
で、何話すんだっけ？
So, what were we supposed to talk about?
え、今日の目的は何なの？
Wait, what's the purpose of today?
そうだよ、何で呼ばれたのかわかってないよ。
That's right, we don't know why we were called here.
なんとね、船長ちょっと... 新... あ、ちょっと言えないけど。重大発表があって。
Actually, I have a little... New... Oh, I can't say it yet. But I have a big announcement.
何？ 何なに？ 聞かせて、聞かせて！
What? What is it? Tell us, tell us!
この次、発表なんですよ！
The announcement is coming up next!
えー！？ このあとすぐ！？ 本当に？
What!? Right after this!? Really?
え、早く見たいから終わるか。
Well, I want to see it soon, so let's finish up.
そーね、じゃ解散！
Right, well then, disband!
3、2、1... あんなっちゃってー！
3, 2, 1... Announce it!
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
田中公平
Tanaka Kouhei
取り戻す...
To take back...
取り戻すこと誓う
I swear to take it back.
光りあれ 勇気の旗掲げて
Let there be light. Raise the flag of courage
旅立とう 嵐の海
and let's set sail into the stormy sea.
立ち上がれ 幸せは願えば
Stand up. Happiness isn't so cheap
手に入るほど 安くはない
that you can get it just by wishing.
守るために戦うなら
If you fight to protect,
海賊となればいい
then you should become a pirate.
22時プレミア公開!
Premiere at 22:00!
マリン出航!!
Marine Set Sail!!
世界が壊れてゆく
The world was breaking,
泣き声が聞こえていた
I could hear the crying voices.
汚れた拳 痛むほど
I clenched my stained fists
強く握った
so tight it hurt.
当たり前に笑っていた
Yesterday, when we laughed
昨日はもう どこにもない
as a matter of course, is nowhere to be found.
明日がどんな日になるのか
No one knows
誰も知らない
what kind of day tomorrow will be.
正義にさえ 捨てられた今日
Today, even abandoned by justice,
取り戻すこと誓う
I swear to take it back.
光りあれ 勇気の旗掲げて
Let there be light. Raise the flag of courage
旅立とう 嵐の海
and let's set sail into the stormy sea.
立ち上がれ 幸せは願えば
Stand up. Happiness isn't so cheap
手に入るほど 安くはない
that you can get it just by wishing.
守るために戦うなら
If you fight to protect,
海賊となればいい
then you should become a pirate.
幸せは簡単に
Happiness easily
灰の中消えてしまう
vanishes into ashes.
奇跡をただ見てることが
If you can't forgive yourself
許せないなら
for just watching the miracle...
一人きりで震えていた
The weak self that was trembling
弱い自分 消えはしない
all alone won't disappear.
それでも決意胸にだけは
But with determination in my heart,
もう迷わない
I will no longer hesitate.
道半ばで 倒れた友に
To the friend who fell halfway...
託された言葉抱き
Clutching the words entrusted to me.
光りあれ 自由の旗掲げて
Let there be light. Raise the flag of freedom
進め 大海原
and advance into the great ocean.
燃え上がれ どんな雨だろうと
Burn up. No matter what kind of rain it is,
消えることなき 火になれ
become a fire that never goes out.
光りあれ 勇気の旗掲げて
Let there be light. Raise the flag of courage
旅立とう 嵐の海
and let's set sail into the stormy sea.
立ち上がれ 幸せは願えば
Stand up. Happiness isn't so cheap
手に入るほど 安くはない
that you can get it just by wishing.
守るために戦うなら
If you fight to protect,
海賊となればいい
then you should become a pirate.
ヨーホッホッハローヘイ
Yo ho ho, hello hey.
ホッヘイ ホッヘイ ホッヘイ
Ho hey, ho hey, ho hey.
ヨーホッホッハローヘイ
Yo ho ho, hello hey.
恐れずにここで
Without fear, here...
あかつきの 勝利の鐘に
At the chime of the dawn of victory,
立ち上がれ
stand up!
ヨーホッホッハローヘイ
Yo ho ho, hello hey.
ホッヘイ ホッヘイ ホッヘイ
Ho hey, ho hey, ho hey.
独りきりいた
I was all alone,
集まれば ほら
but if we gather, see...
風を待て
Wait for the wind
偉大なる海賊団だ
The great pirate crew
錨上げ
Raise the anchor
出航！！
Set sail!!
マリン出航！！
作曲：田中公平
編曲：田中公平
作詞：砂守岳央
Marine Set Sail!!
Composition: Kohei Tanaka
Arrangement: Kohei Tanaka
Lyrics: Takeo Sunamori
船長の新曲、マリン出航！！
The Captain's new song, Marine Set Sail!!
船長が一番好きな作曲家、田中公平先生に作っていただきました。
It was composed by my favorite composer, Kohei Tanaka-sensei.
本日、24時から各種音楽サイトにて配信開始！
It'll be available on various music sites starting today at midnight!
そしてこの後すぐ、アニメミュージックビデオ、プレミア公開です！
And right after this, the anime music video premiere will begin!
それでは、行きますよ。出航！！
Alright then, here we go. Set sail!!
新曲お披露目！
マリン出航！！
3D LIVE
ゲストあり！
New song reveal!
Marine Set Sail!!
3D LIVE
Guests included!